至善之地
前情提要
翻译: 酷酷西红柿 Milk 牙牙
我的推断很严谨
There's no escaping it.
问题出在
The problem...
校对: 钟钟
我身上
Is me.
现在
and now...
是我该离开的时候了 永别了
I have to leave you... Forever.
后期: A酥
Michael 不可能是你的错
Michael, you can't be the problem.
压制: 凯撒
就是我的错
Oh, but I am.
要知道 建筑师是不允许住在
You see, architects aren't supposed to live
自己设计的社区里的
In the neighborhoods they design,
但我太爱人类了 所以 我想试一试
But I love humans, so I-I wanted to try.
现在我明白这是个错误了
I see now that was a mistake.
我的掺和才是社区所有的灾难里
My meddling is the one true constant
唯一没变的因素
In all of our disasters.
我想强迫着Jianyu打开心扉
I tried to force Jianyu into opening up,
结果打开了一个地洞
Which caused a sinkhole to open up.
我把只小狗狗踢到了太阳上去
I kicked a puppy into the sun,
天就下起了垃圾雨
And garbage rained down.
我完全低估了迎新晚宴上
I grossly underestimated the number of shrimp needed
需要供应的虾的数量
For the opening-night party,
第二天就飞得漫天都是
And what flew through the sky the next day,
为了嘲讽我失败了吗
Taunting me for my failures?
对不起大家 真的很对不起
I'm sorry, everyone. I'm truly sorry.
Janet
Janet?
给我叫辆火车送我退休吧
Please call a train to escort me into retirement.
跟你们讲 出入社区唯一的途径
You see, the only way in and out of a neighborhood
就是坐火车
Is by train,
Janet是唯一可以操纵火车的人
And Janet is the only one who can operate them.
亲爱的Janet
Oh, my dear Janet.
我走掉的话你没关系吧
Will you be okay after I leave?
没事儿
Yes.
完全不会对我有任何影响
This will not affect me in any way.
天呐 能不能有点同情心
Jeez, show some compassion.
因为 我无法感到悲伤
Well, I can't feel sad,
我能做到最接近人类哭的事情就是
But here's my best approximation of human crying.
唔啊哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇
Baaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaah!
- Janet 我真是太感动了  - 那就好
- Oh, Janet, that was beautiful. - Yeah.
至善之地
第一季 第七集
电波诚译
第七章
你都跟他说了些啥
What did you say to him?
是你叫他这么做的吗
Did you make him do this somehow?
没有 这完全是他自己的主意
Nope, this was entirely his idea.
老兄 这是个好消息啊
Dude, this is good news.
Michael会安安然然地退休
Michael's gonna get a chill retirement,
老实说 他也该安然一会儿了
Which, frankly, he desperately needs,
而我终于可以松口气
And I can finally relax.
他叉的太完美了
It's forking perfect.
不 这糟透了 Michael搞错了
No, it's terrible. Michael's wrong.
错不在他
He's not the problem.
但的确是他把我带来这的啊
Well, Michael did bring me here,
就是这个错误才导致了后面这些岔子
Which was the mistake that led to all the other problems.
所以这么说来 的确错就在他
So, in that sense, he is the real problem.
哈 这推理你怎么看 大伦理学家
Ha! How do you like them ethics?
我甩了你一脸伦理呢 Chidi
I just ethics'd you in the face, Chidi!
这也没有改变我们在撒谎的事实
It doesn't change the fact that we weren't truthful.
在中国有句古老的谚语
There's an old Chinese proverb--
"谎言呀像老虎
"Lies are like tigers.
凶起来猛着呢"
They are bad."
- 就没了  - 用汉语讲起来更诗意的
- That's it? - It's more poetic in mandarin.
Michael是要退休
Look, Michael is retiring.
他会乘条天使般的小船
He's gonna be on an angel boat
去抽月光做的雪茄呢
Somewhere smoking moonbeam cigars.
Tahani要给他办个欢送派对
Now, Tahani is throwing him a good-bye party.
我们去搭把手吧
Let's go help out.
好的 这样我们就能弥补
Sure, that will more than make up
带给他的伤害痛苦和谎言了
For the pain and misery and lying.
对啊 你总算开窍了
Yes, now you're getting it.
嗨 Chidi 刚刚读完你的关于
Hey, Chidi, just read your article
逻辑实证主义的论文 太 枯燥了
On logical positivism-- so dry.
啊 谢谢了 Henry
Oh, thanks, Henry.
新靴子呀
Whoa! New boots.
嗯 是的 刚买的
Oh, yeah, just got 'em.
在商店第一眼看到 我就惊得
Saw them in the store, and I was just like,
"哇喔噢"
"Whoa!"
跟我说实话 你喜欢吗
Tell the truth-- do you like 'em?
啊
Oh.
- 啊 喜欢  - 没有太红了吗
- Oh, yeah. - Not too red?
- 没有  - 水钻没有太多吗
- No. - Crystals aren't too much?
水钻一点也不多
Crystals are not too much.
好 你这么说我就放心多了
Oh, well, that makes me feel much better
因为我一直拿不定主意
because I was really going back and forth
不知道这靴子到底值不值这价钱
Over whether they were worth the money.
这双靴子超级贵的
They were super expensive.
是啊 看起来 超赞
Yeah, well, they're, uh, amazing.
这是我这辈子见过最赞的靴子了
Those are the coolest boots I've ever seen in my life.
多谢夸奖 哥们
Thanks so much, buddy.
没事 拜
Right. Bye.
我的天呐
My god...
我都做了些什么啊
What have I done?
今晚我们要完美地将 欢庆与敬佩
Tonight needs to be the perfect blend of celebratory, reverential
苦辣酸甜 欢欣鼓舞 和 轻松自在 融合起来
Bittersweet, upbeat, fun, and effortless.
这将是 话题 "Tahani的美好时光"
This is #tahanitime.
这是在干嘛
What is all this?
啊不行 Michael
Oh, no, Michael,
你不该来这看的 还没布置好呢
You're not supposed to see it till it's all set up.
既然来了 欢迎来到你的退休派对
But, well, welcome to your retirement party.
瞧那边 我布置好了餐台
Look, over there, I've even set up a buffet
都是主题甜品 像退休薄荷巧克力蛋糕
Of themed desserts, like retire-mint chocolate cake
还有 "远行馅饼 "
Or, uh, "Flan voyage."
噢 天呐
Oh, boy.
这边还布置了一个皮纳塔
Oh, and here we have a pinata
照着你做的 和你一样有意思
Shaped like you, which is always fun.
还要问一下 你最喜欢什么颜色
By the way, uh, what's your favorite color
我好来挑桌布
For the tablecloths?
是种人类眼睛无法感悟的颜色
Well, it's not perceptible by human eyes.
叫做"胸膛荣光"
It's called "Pleurigloss."
你能描述一下吗
Could you describe it?
就像是
It's the color of...
一个士兵刚从战场下来回到家
When a soldier comes home from war
第一眼看到自己狗狗的那种颜色
And sees his dog for the first time.
嗯 不如就蓝色吧
Hmm. How about blue?
Tahani 很抱歉
Tahani, I'm so sorry.
我们得马上取消这个派对
We need to cancel this party immediately.
为什么啊
But why?
对于我这样的人
For a being like me,
退休
Retirement...
可不是件好玩的事
Is not something fun.
那"退休"对于你是什么样的
What is "Retirement" for you exactly?
我本来不想跟你们讲的 怕影响情绪
Well, I wasn't gonna share this so as not to upset you,
但 其实是种
But it's, a--
是种极端的惩罚形式
An extreme form of punishment.
我们叫它"万年尖叫"
We call it "The eternal shriek."
我的灵魂会被打散
My soul will be disintegrated,
每一个分子都会散落异处
And each molecule will be placed
在各个炽灼的太阳表面焚烧殆尽
On the surface of a different burning sun.
还会把我的 我的精髓从躯体中剜出
And then my--my essence will be scooped out of my body
用一把赤热的小勺浇在滚烫的钻石上
With a flaming ladle and poured over hot diamonds.
钻石听起来蛮好的啊
Oh, but the diamonds sound lovely.
一点儿也不好
They're not...
我身体余下的部分
And then what's left of my body
会永远地被一根钛合金棒子棍打
Will be endlessly beaten with a titanium rod,
就像
Like a--
就像个皮纳塔一样
Like a pinata.
没错 只不过你们把吊绳系在我的腰上
Yes, except you have the string around my waist,
他们会把绳子系在我的生殖器上
But instead it will definitely be around my genitals.
- 天呐  - Michael 真的很抱歉
- What? - Oh, Michael, I'm so sorry.
我只是想要纪念你
I was just trying to honor you.
请你让我重新构思一下这个活动
Please, allow me to reconceive the event.
没问题
Of course.
好了 大家伙儿 我们得从头开始
All right, everyone, we're starting over.
今晚的主题换成"阴郁"
The key word for tonight is just "Somber."
Jianyu 亲爱的 我们得把这些
Jianyu, my love, we're gonna have to get rid of
派对小拉炮都处理掉 就现在
all of the party poppers immediately.
不 不是拉掉他们
No, not by using them.
停 Jianyu 打住
No, Jianyu. Done.
他会受折磨
He's gonna be tortured?
见鬼 我就差一点就完美地
Dang it. I was almost handed a perfect solution
不费一点功夫解决掉我所有的麻烦了
To all my problems without having to work for it at all,
现在都泡汤了
And now it's gone.
为什么坏事总是落到平平凡凡的人头上
Why do bad things always happen to mediocre people?
我们只是为保身份撒个小谎啊
Who are lying about their identities?
你有两个选择
Okay, you have two options.
你可以坦白真相救Michael一把
You can confess and save Michael,
或者你可以继续撒谎
Or you can continue to lie
置Michael于万劫不复的痛苦之中
And condemn him to an eternity of unimaginable pain.
或者 第三个选项
Or option c--
撒我自己的谎
Continue to lie about myself
然后找个法子救救Michael
And find a way to save Michael.
有什么方法能把Tahani推进火坑的吗
Can we somehow throw Tahani under the bus?
这样就会是典型的
That would be a classic
"一石二鸟"情况了
"Two birds with one stone" Scenario.
而且 我还可以住进她的房子
Plus, I'd get her house.
一石三鸟
three birds.
没有 除了坦白没有别的方法了
No, there's no way to stop this except confessing.
现在随时随刻 Michael都有可能上火车
Any moment now, Michael is going to get on that train,
我们就再也见不到他了
And we will never see him again,
就像Lindeman教授
Just like professor Lindeman
我请他再读一遍我3600页的手稿之后
After I asked him to reread my 3,600-page manuscript.
他说他抽光了所有的烟
He said he was going out for cigarettes,
然后辞掉了巴黎索邦学院的终身教职离开了
But then he just left his tenured position at the Sorbonne.
好一段故事 Janet
Great story. Janet?
哈喽
hi, there.
嗨 唯一的
Hi. So the only way
离开社区的方法就是火车对吧
Out of the neighborhood is a train?
没错 我是唯一一个
That's correct. I am the only one
能召唤火车的人 得要我才能操纵它
Who can call the train, and it needs me to operate.
还有个问题 可能会有点儿奇怪
One more question, and, um, this is a little weird,
但我们能
But can we...
关掉你吗
Uh, shut you down?
能 好问题
Yes, great question.
有一个自毁开关
There is a kill switch
就在社区里一个偏僻的地方
In a remote sector of the neighborhood
如果我出了故障
In the event that I malfunction
或者企图伤害这里的居民
And attempt to harm the residents.
要是你按下开关 我将被摧毁
If you press it, I will be destroyed.
- 还有别的问题吗  - 没了 很好 谢谢
- Anything else? - No, that's good, thanks.
- 好的  - 哇哦 你想杀了Janet
- Okay. - Whoa, you want to kill Janet?
如果Michael不离开的话他就没法退休
Michael can't retire if he can't leave.
况且他也走不了 如果没有Janet
He can't leave if there's no Janet
开火车的话
To run the train.
这是个完美的解决方案
It's a perfect solution.
Janet 击个掌怎么样
Janet, high five, please?
谢谢 亲爱的
Thanks, babe.
你可不能杀了Janet
You cannot kill Janet
杀人可是众所周知
Killing is one of the most famous
最不道德的禁止事项之一
Moral no-nos.
Janet是被送到这儿帮助我们的非人类存在体
Janet is a nonhuman object who was sent here to help us,
而她帮我们的方法就是让我们杀了她
And the way she can help us is if we kill her.
我们做的只是稍带点谋杀意味的事
We're doing one small murder-y thing
出于一个更远大 更好的理由
For a bigger, better reason.
只要目的正当 可以不择手段
The ends justify the means.
你知道这话是谁说的吗
Do you know who said that?
是不是某个美好又善良的人 就像Oprah
Was it someone nice and great, like Oprah?
Oprah：美国电视节目主持人
是Machiavelli说的
It was Machiavelli...
Machiavelli：马基雅弗利，意大利新兴资产阶级思想政治家、历史学家
一个跟Oprah一点边不沾的人
a very non-Oprah-like figure.
我们杀了她之后会怎样
And what happens after we kill her?
我们不得不就我们做的事向每个人撒谎
We'll have to lie to everyone about what we did,
撒谎始终是错的
And lying is always wrong.
为什么 为什么我要告诉Henry我喜欢他的靴子
Why? Why would I tell Henry that I liked his boots?
我不喜欢 我讨厌他的靴子
I don't like his boots. I hate his boots.
是的 我知道
Yes, I know.
两天前你就跟我说过了
You've talked about it for the last two days.
我对他撒谎了 你写的论文是关于康德的
I lied to him. You wrote your thesis on Kant.
康德认为撒谎在道德上始终是错的
He believed that lying is always morally wrong--
没有例外
No exceptions.
没错 康德是个孤独且痴迷于宗教的隐士
Yes, well, Kant was a lonely, obsessive hermit
他一个朋友也没有
With zero friends.
有时我们做事只是出于礼貌
Sometimes we do thing just to be polite,
但如果你真的对这件事耿耿于怀
But if you really feel that strongly about it,
那就告诉他真相
Tell him the truth.
而且 我也不在乎
Also, I don't care,
因为现在已经是午夜了
'cause it's the middle of the night.
这就是为什么人人都讨厌伦理学家
This is why everyone hates moral philosophy professors.
有吗
They do?
嘿 Chidi
Hey, Chidi.
- 你今天来听我的课了  - 嗯 是的 没错
- You sit in on my class today? - Uh, I did, yeah.
很棒的课 顺便说一句—非常出色
Great lecture, by the way-- so bleak.
谢谢 伙计
Thanks, bud.
你来听课真是太完美了
It's actually perfect that you are here.
我有东西给你
I got something for you.
噢 老天
Oh, my god.
你很喜欢我的那双
You loved mine so much,
所以我决定给你一双属于你自己的
I decided to get you your own pair.
我们可以当靴子兄弟了
We can be boot brothers.
哇 这个我不能收 这靴子太贵了
Wow. I can't accept these. They're too expensive.
你当然可以收下 快试试 朋友
Sure you can. Try 'em on, mate.
你这么喜欢我的靴子
The fact that you liked mine so much
让我觉得买下他们是个正确的决定
Really made me feel like I made the right choice to buy them.
毕竟 不该只有我享受乐趣和好靴子 对吧
After all, why should I have all the fun and boots, eh?
我 我不 我不知道
I-I don't--I don't know.
看起来棒极了
Those look great.
穿着它们转一圈
Take 'em for a spin.
你简直帅的飞起
you're flying.
嗯 谢谢
Mm, thanks.
发表演讲了 演讲时间到了 各位
Speeches! Time for speeches, everyone.
Michael 作为一个并没有真正
Michael, as someone who didn't exactly have
接受过完整父母教导的人
The steadiest parental guidance,
我只想谢谢您
I just want to thank you.
你总是在那儿守护着我们
You were always there for us.
我本不该那样的 我是个麻烦
I shouldn't have been. I was the problem.
是的 但
Yes, but...
你不在的时候一切也都很好
It was also great when you weren't there.
别担心 很快我就不在了 永远不在
Don't worry. Soon I won't be...Forever.
因为那万年尖叫
Because of the eternal shriek!
是的 谢谢你 Glenn
Yes, thank you, Glenn.
我想说的是
Look, what I'm trying to say is this--
Michael 你总是给我们温暖还有安全感
Michael, you always kept us warm and safe
像那明亮而炙热的太阳
Like a bright, glowing sun.
像我踢了只狗上去那个
Like the one I kicked the dog into
还是我将在其美好温暖的表面
Or the one I'm going to be burned
被烧焦的那个
On the surface of fraternity?
好了 没有别的发言了
Okay, no more speeches.
演讲结束
Speeches are over.
现在Michael准备讲话了
Michael's going to talk now.
啊 我很抱歉我之前脾气太暴躁
Ugh, I'm sorry I was so grumpy.
我只是因为必须要离开而有点难过
It's just I'm sad that I have to leave
我还没做完那些
Before doing all the human things
我想做的人类的事
That I wanted to do.
我想把头发弄湿
I wanted to get my hair wet.
知道吗 我 我想试着拉伤一下腿筋
You know, I-I wanted to pull a hamstring.
搞清楚"向着"和"朝着"的区别
To learn the difference between "Toward" And "Towards."
我想试试当你沿着过道走的时候
I wanted to do that thing where you walk down the hallway,
迎面走来另一个人
And someone else is walking the other way,
你们都靠向同一边
And then you both lean to one side
然后又同时靠向另一边
And then the other,
然后你们为这种共同的小失误暗暗发笑
And then you both chuckle over your shared foible.
我想要一张优惠卡
I wanted to get a rewards card,
什么优惠卡都行
Any rewards card.
我 我想跟人简单谈谈然后说
I-I wanted to talk briefly to someone and then say,
"污一点儿没事"
"Take it sleazy."
我想吃一块苏打饼干
I wanted to eat a saltine.
噢 其实我有一些苏打饼干
Oh! I actually have some saltines.
给 尝尝
Here, try this.
太干了
Pretty dry...
而且太咸
And too salty.
行了 低调地从这儿出去吧
Well, going out on a real low note here.
好的 再见 各位
Okay, bye, everyone.
嗯 污一点儿没事
Well, take it sleazy.
你说了那句话
You got to say it?
是的 然后你就可以回我一句
Yes, but then you say it back.
不 这一点儿不自然
No, it's not organic.
嗯 Janet 这儿有过多少个"Janet"
Uh, Janet, how many "Janets" Have there been?
共二十五代"Janet"
There have been 25 generations of janet.
每个升级版的Janet都会更有智慧
Each new update of Janet gains more wisdom
有更强的社会能力
And social abilities.
有趣的是 第一代Janet有个点击式触摸转盘
Fun fact--the first janet had a click wheel.
那它跟人一样会变老吗
So it's like aging for a human?
你 你会长大吗
You're--you're growing up?
我也很想那样 Chidi
That's how I like to think of it, chidi.
我不能吃东西 所以每次有新版的Janet诞生
I can't eat, so every time there's a new version of janet,
我喜欢拿一块生日蛋糕
I like to take a piece of birthday cake
朝我嘴的部位拍上去
And smash it around where my mouth is.
看 Janet已经 已经会学习和成长了
Look, janet has-- has learned and grown.
她有真正的生活 我们不能杀了她
She's essentially living a life. We can't kill her.
你这样的态度 我们当然不能
Not with that attitude, we can't.
听着 伙计 我死了 你也死了
Listen, man, I'm dead, you're dead,
我们都死了 现在我们再杀了她
We all died, and now we're killing her.
继续传承下去
Pay it forward.
嗯 不 这句话不是这么说的
Uh, no, that's not what that means at all.
Eleanor
Eleanor?
我们在这儿
Here we are .
只要按下那个按钮 然后就永别了 Janet
Just press that button, and it's good-bye, janet.
Chidi 我看得出你在担心
Chidi, I can see that you're worried,
我只想向你保证
And I just want to assure you,
我并不是人类 我也感觉不到痛
I am not human, and I cannot feel pain.
啊 谢谢 这起了点作用
Ah, thank you. That helps.
但是 我必须警告你
However, I should warn you--
我的程序里带有一套自动防故障措施
I am programmed with a fail-safe measure.
当你靠近自毁开关时
As you approach the kill switch,
我会求你饶命
I will begin to beg for my life.
那是为防止意外停机而设置的
It's just there in case of an accidental shut down,
但会看起来很逼真
But it will seem very real.
酷 所以谁来做这个 我还是你
Cool. So who's doing this, me or you?
我想我来吧
I think I have to.
嗯 不知为什么 当个旁观者看起来更糟
Um, being a bystander seems worse, somehow.
好的 开始吧
Okay, here we go.
Chidi 不 不 不 Chidi 求你了
Chidi, no, no, no! Chidi, please!
求求你 求求你 求你不要伤害我
Please, please, please don't hurt me.
我不想死 拜托 拜托了
I don't want to die! Please, please--
啊
Ah!
再说一次 我不是人类
Again, I am not human.
我不会死的
I can't die.
我只是被人格化的盛装知识的容器
I am simply an anthropomorphized vessel of knowledge
为便利你的生活而被制造的
Built to make your life easier.
你的求饶看起来太真实了
You're pleading seems so real.
噢 是的 这是个很有用的自动防故障措施
Oh, yes, it is a very effective fail-safe.
啊 是我想杀机器人的 对吗
Ugh, you want a robot killed right,
所以得自己动手
You have to do it yourself.
Eleanor Eleanor 不 不 不
Eleanor? Eleanor, no, no, no.
拜托了 等等 等等 等等 等等 Eleanor 我还有孩子
Please, wait, wait, wait, wait. Eleanor, I have kids.
我有三个漂亮的孩子
I have three beautiful children--
Tyler Emma还有小宝贝Phillip
Tyler, Emma, and little, tiny baby Phillip.
看看Tyler
Look at Tyler.
他有哮喘 但他像个冠军一样跟病魔战斗
Tyler has asthma, but he is battling it like a champ.
看看他 不 Eleanor 看着他
Look at him. No, Eleanor, look at them.
看着他们
Look at them!
look at them!
啊 这太逼真了
Aah! It's so realistic!
Eleanor 再说一次 我不是人类
Eleanor, again, I'm not human.
这是张素材照片
This is a stock photo of the crowd
尼克儿童频道"孩子的选择"奖上的照片
At the Nickelodeon kids' choice awards.
没错 这不是真的
that's right, it's not real.
让我们搞定它 好的
Let's just do this. Right.
求你了 我还有很多事要做
Please, I have so much to live for.
- 不 不 不 求你了  - 我们还没靠近那儿
- No, no, no, please. - We're not even near the--
嘿 伙计们 怎么了
Hey, guys, what's going on?
那个聚会太差劲了 所以我溜了
That party was lame, so I bailed.
然后我看到你们 跟着你们来到这儿
Then I saw you, so I followed you here.
噢 瞧 一个按钮 不 不 不
Oh, look, a button. No, no, no!
Jianyu 不
Jianyu, no!
啊 老兄 我想按那个按钮
Ah, man, I wanted to push that button.
不地道啊 兄弟
Not cool, dude.
哇 Janet怎么了
Whoa. What happened to Janet?
她 她死了 我 我杀了她
She's--she's dead. I-I-I killed her.
不是杀死
Not killed.
记得吗 Janet不是一个生物
Remember, Janet was not a living being,
所以她不会被杀死
So she can't be killed.
"请注意 我被杀害了"
"Attention-- I have been murdered."
"请注意"
"Attention..."
我们怎么办啊 Eleanor
What do we do, Eleanor?
什么怎么办
What do we do?
Chidi 你刚杀死了Janet
Chidi, you just murdered Janet.
我们得赶紧离开犯罪现场
We have to flee your crime scene.
跑啊
Run!
"我被杀害了"
"I have been murdered. "
- 对不起啊 Janet  - "我被杀害了"
- Sorry, Janet! - "I have been murdered."
"请注意 我被"
"Attention--I have--"
"请注意 我被杀害了"
"Attention-- I have been murdered."
好 兄弟 速成教学 做了坏事不被逮着
Okay, dude, crash course in getting away with bad stuff.
你得表现的镇定跟没事儿一样
You have to act calm and cool
就像你跟这世界一毛钱关系都没有
like you don't have a care in the world.
能行吗
Okay?
很好
Great.
哦 哇 看 简直就是<老板度假去>
Oh, wow. Look, it's "Weekend at bernie's,"
<老板度假去> 1989年美国电影 里面有死人戴墨镜强装活人的情节
就像电影里戴了副太阳镜的死人
'cause you're a dead guy in sunglasses.
看多好玩儿啊 是不是 Chidi
We have fun, don't we, Chidi?
我这一辈子从来没有这么大压力过
I've never been more stressed out in my entire life.
我知道你需要点儿啥
I know what you need.
Janet 你能给Chidi搞点大麻来吗
Janet, can you get Chidi some weed?
哦 对了 你弄死了Janet
Oh, that's right. You killed Janet.
Janet被人杀害了
Well, Janet's been murdered.
真是给这个好日子又带来一个亮点
That's a nice capper to this wonderful day.
我现在还不清楚这是怎么回事
I don't really know what happens now
因为Janet从未被人杀害过
because Janet has never been murdered before--
走好 Janet
安息吧 我们逝去的姐妹
只是今天 在我眼皮子底下
Only today, here on my watch,
我是被派对分散了注意力
while I was distracted with a party that
这个派对是Tahani为我张罗的
Tahani was throwing for me,
然而我并不想要
which I didn't want.
Michael 你可千万别怪自己啊
Michael, you mustn't blame yourself.
我没有 我在怪你
I'm not. I'm blaming you.
话说回来 关于Janet还有什么可说的呢
Anyway, what is there to say about Janet
还有哪些没被警报说到的呢
that hasn't already been said by the
就是天空上巨大的Janet警报
giant Janet alarm in the sky?
"我被人杀害了"
"I've been murdered"!
我觉得这道出了一切
I think that says it all.
你好呀
Hello.
Janet
Janet,
你复活啦
you're alive!
你好 建筑师
Hello, architect,
请输入你的四位数密码
Please enter your four-digit pin.
呃 是啥来着 呃 是啥来着
Uh, what is it? Uh, what is it?
啥来着 哦 对了 对了
What is it? Um--oh, right, right, right!
是 呃 我的出生年份
It's my, uh--my birth year.
呃
Uh...
我得换个密码 这个太好猜了
I got to change that. That's too easy to guess.
Janet
Janet...
是谁杀害了你
Who murdered you?
- 噢 不  - 嘘 没事的
- Oh. Oh, no. - Shh, okay.
- 你好  - 嗯 你好
- Hello. - Yes, hello.
哦
Oh.
对了 呃
Yeah. Uh...
肯定是她的记忆被清除了
Her memory must have been wiped clean,
所以现在要重新上传
So now she's gonna have to re-upload
宇宙中的所有知识
all the knowledge in the universe,
这得花好几天时间 好吧
which will only take a few days. Okay--
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
你好
Hello.
大家好呀
大家 在我搞清楚这件事之前
Everyone, um, until I get to the bottom of this,
我的退休被正式推迟
my retirement is officially postponed.
太好了
Whoo!
你好 你好
Hello. Hello.
你得承认 我算是搞定了
You got to admit-- I kind of nailed it.
我们现在要做的 就是永远保守秘密
All we have to do now is keep the secret forever.
小伙伴J 你能行吗
J-dog, you cool?
我不好 等我到了皮纳塔那儿
No, by the time I got to the piñata,
所有的糖都没了
All the candy was gone.
他不会告诉任何人的
He's not gonna tell anyone.
Chidi 我的小Chidi
Chidi? Cheedster?
你怎么啦
What's, uh, happening, buddy?
你的眼神很奇怪
You have a crazy look in your eye,
你在往自己衬衫里缩
And you're retreating into your shirt.
搞得像缩头乌龟一样
You're kind of turtling.
Henry 你没事吧 怎么啦
Henry, are you all right? What happened?
我长了个动脉瘤
I have an aneurysm.
要做紧急手术
Requires emergency surgery.
医生说我的存活率只有50%
Doctor's give me a 50/50 chance.
所以 如果你想跟我说什么的话
So, if there's anything you need to say to me,
你现在就得说了
You should do it now.
哦
Oh, well...
其实吧
Actually, um...
这里允许穿靴子呢
They let you wear your boots in here?
这是唯一给我带来安慰的东西
They're the only things that bring me comfort.
你刚才想跟我说什么
What did you want to say to me?
哦 呃
Oh, um...
只想说 有我在
Just that I'm here and
我爱你 兄弟
I love you, man.
我也爱你
I love you, too,
靴子兄弟
boot brother.
好嘛
Okay.
悉尼综合医院
Chidi
Chidi!
你不用在这待一整晚的
You didn't have to stay here all night.
手术顺利吗 切除干净了
So surgery went well? All clear?
非常顺利
Right as rain, buddy.
那真是太 太 太好了
That is so, so, so great.
- 我讨厌你的靴子  - 啥
- I hate your boots. - What?
三年前我告诉你我特喜欢你的靴子
I told you that I loved your boots three years ago,
我当时在撒谎
and I was lying,
那时起这个谎就一直跟着我
and that lie has haunted me ever since,
别人一直告诉我没关系的
and people tried to tell me it was fine--
说这只是善意的白色谎言 是社交礼节
just a nice, little white lie in the form of social niceties--
但我不这么想 然后昨天
But I disagreed, and then yesterday
我以为你要走了 但现在你还活着
I thought you were gonna die, but now you're not dead,
我终于可以诚实一回
and I can finally be honest
告诉你这双靴子很丑很糟糕
and say that those boots are terrible and hideous
我讨厌它
and I hate them.
呼
Whoo!
这就是为啥人人都讨厌伦理学教授
This is why everyone hates moral philosophy professors.
嗯 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我也明白
And I get it.
我不管她复活了
I don't care that she came back
或者我们是出于好意
or that we did it for a good reason.
我受不了活在谎言中
I can't live with this lie.
我要去自首 承认自己杀了Janet
I'm going to confess to the murder of Janet.
啥
What?
老兄 为啥想不开
Dude, Why?
Janet好得很
Janet is fine.
我们没伤到她一根汗毛
We didn't harm her at all.
没有么
We didn't?
嘿 Janet
Hey, Janet?
你好
Hello.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
Janet 麻烦你背一下英文字母表好吗
Janet, would you please recite the English alphabet?
A B
A-B...
Janet
Janet.
她知道A B Janet
She knows her a-b-Janets.
她是真的知道宇宙中的一切知识
She literally knew everything in the universe,
现在却变成了婴儿
and now she's a baby.
而且就算她没事
And even if she were okay,
对我来说骗人太痛苦
it would be too painful for me
我受不了一直骗人
to live with these lies.
你在胡说八道什么呢
What are you talking about?
撒谎骗人相当简单啊
It is so easy to live with a lie.
有一次我假装自己有绝症
I once pretended to have a terminal illness
就在太阳眼镜店里见到了Scott Wolf
to meet Scott Wolf at a Sunglass Hut.
Scott Wolf 美国演员 出演美剧<夜班医生><罪案第六感><五口之家>
没有受害者的罪行
Victimless crime.
行吧
Fine.
我不会说出去 因为我答应了要帮你
I won't say anything because I promised to help you,
至于我们的所作所为
and the moral implications of...
折射出的道德内涵 实在太错综复杂
everything that we've done are so complicated
我可能永远都理不清楚 但我还是讨厌撒谎
that I may never untangle them, but I hate lying.
我一直都讨厌
I always have,
这事会把我生吞活剥的
and this is going to eat me up inside forever.
你能做到不屑一顾 忘了就算
You might be able to shrug this off and forget about it,
但我永远不能
but I never will.
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
Jianyu
Jianyu!
Michael Janet说你想找我聊聊
Michael, Janet said you wanted to speak to me.
其实她只是一直在流口水
Well, actually, she was just drooling a lot
不停地说"你好"
and saying "Hello"
说了一遍又一遍
over and over again,
不过她确实往你这边指
but she did point at you.
我欠你一个道歉
I owe you an apology.
噢 别 不需要的
Oh, no. No, you don't.
不过你请继续
But please continue.
你只是想帮忙
You were only trying to help.
你是一个特别好的人
You're a wonderful person,
如果我还有机会开退休派对
And if I ever do have a retirement party,
我希望是你来策划
I hope you plan it.
大家好 谢谢你们过来
Thank you for gathering, everyone.
我想给大家汇报一下新进展
I want to keep you all updated.
就我目前所知
Here's what we know.
有人杀死了Janet
Someone slaughtered Janet.
哦 天哪
Oh, boy.
- 天哪  - 没事的
- Oh, boy. - Okay.
我猜测这个可怕的事件
I assume that this horrifying act
多少都与这里之前发生的事情有关联
is somehow related to the other issues we've had here.
这也意味着
It also means
这个社区里出现的问题
that the problems in this neighborhood
并非百分百是我的责任
are not 100% my fault.
有一些什么别的东西在搞事
There is something else at work here.
如果关于此事
If anyone has any information
有人有任何消息
about any of this,
我请求你
I beg you,
告诉我
tell me.
嘿 我爱你
Hey, I love you, man.
Michael
Michael...
社区里的大麻烦
The problem in the neighborhood...
是我
is me.
我是误入善地的
I was brought to the good place by mistake.
我本不应该来这里
I'm not supposed to be here.
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组